Guide to the Brooklyn periodical illustrations BCMS.0003
Brooklyn Collection
Brooklyn periodical illustrations
1839-1968
1884-1904
Brooklyn Collection
BCMS.0003
10.8 Linear Feet in 8 flat boxes.
This collection covers more than a century of Brooklyn history, with periodical illustrations depicting historic people, structures and events in Brooklyn predominantly from the era before the rise of photography.
Conditions Governing Access
Open to researchers without restriction.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This is a composite collection from many different sources, predominantly purchases.
Arrangement
Materials are arranged into series by subject. Within each series, the items are listed alphabetically by title.
Related Materials
King, Moses. King's Views of Brooklyn. New York: M. King, 1904. 917.472 K53
Stiles, Henry. The civil, political, professional and ecclesiastical history and commercial and industrial record of the County of Kings and the City of Brooklyn, N.Y. from 1683 to 1884. New York: Munsell, 1884. F127.K5 S8 1884
Harper's Weekly, Scientific American, and Ballou's Pictorial Drawing-Room Companion are available digitally on Hathi Trust.
Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper and American Architect and Building News are available digitally on the Internet Archive and Hathi Trust.
Gleason's Pictorial Drawing Room Companion is available digitally on the Internet Archive.
Scope and Contents
Many of the illustrations in this collection come from popular magazines and journals of the 19th century, including Harper's Weekly, Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, and Scientific American. Many are also taken from Henry R. Stiles's History of Kings County (see "Related Materials" for bibliographic information). The bulk dates of the collection are 1884–1904; images dated after 1930 are generally reprints of 19th century prints.
Prints
- Architecture
  - A.D. Matthews' Sons Department Store, Fulton Street. King's Views of Brooklyn, 1904 (Box 1)
  - Abraham Abraham Residence, 800 St. Mark's Avenue. King's Views of Brooklyn, 1904 (Box 1)
  - Abraham and Strauss Department Store. King's Views of Brooklyn, 1904 (Box 1)
  - Academy of Design, Brooklyn N.Y.; Messrs. J.C. Cady and H.M. Congdon, Architects. The New York Sketchbook of Architecture, 1876 (Box 1)
  - Adelphi Academy. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884 (Box 1)
  - Ansonia Clock Company. King's Views of Brooklyn, 1904 (Box 1)
  - Armory, Twenty Third Regiment N.G.S.N.Y. Clermont Ave between Myrtle and Willoughby Aves, undated (Box 1)
  - The Art Association Building, Montague Street, Brooklyn. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884 (Box 1)
  - The Assembly (Wilson Building), 153-157 Pierrepont Street. King's Views of Brooklyn, 1904 (Box 1)
  - Atlantic Dock, Brooklyn, undated (Box 1)
  - The Baptist Home. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884 (Box 1)
  - Botanical Museum of the Brooklyn Institute of Arts & Sciences; Detail of Central Pavilion; Interior of Central Pavilion; McKim, Mead & White, undated (Box 1)
  - Botanical Museum of the Brooklyn Institute of Arts & Sciences; Façade toward Garden; Façade toward Street; McKim, Mead & White, undated (Box 1)
  - Brooklyn Association for Improving the Condition of the Poor. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884 (Box 1)
  - Brooklyn Athenaeum. Ballou's Pictorial Drawing Room Companion, 1855 (Box 1)
  - Brooklyn Industrial School and Home for Destitute Children. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884 (Box 1)
  - The Brooklyn Institute. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884 (Box 1)
  - The Brooklyn Institute of Arts & Sciences; Central Portico, North Elevation; Detail of North Façade; McKim, Mead & White, undated (Box 1)
  - The Brooklyn Institute of Arts & Sciences; Complete Block Plan; McKim, Mead & White, undated (Box 1)
  - The Brooklyn Institute of Arts & Sciences; Corridor of Antique Sculpture, First Floor; Hall of Renaissance Sculpture, Third Floor; McKim, Mead & White, undated (Box 1)
  - The Brooklyn Institute of Arts & Sciences; North Façade; McKim, Mead & White, undated (Box 1)
  - The Brooklyn Nursery. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884. (Box 1)
  - Brooklyn Orphan Asylum. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884. (Box 1)
  - The Brooklyn Society for the Relief of Respectable Aged Indigent Females [The Graham Institution]. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884. (Box 1)
  - Charles Adolph Schieren Residence, 405 Clinton Avenue. King's Views of Brooklyn, 1904. (Box 1)
  - Charles O. Gates Residence, 45 Plaza, opposite main entrance to Prospect Park. King's Views of Brooklyn, 1904 (Box 1)
  - "The Circle" [Park Slope]. Detroit Photographic Company, undated. (Box 1)
  - City Hall, Brooklyn, New York. Gleason's Pictorial, 1854 (Box 1)
  - City Hall, Brooklyn, N.Y. Gleason's Pictorial Drawing Room Companion, 1851 (Box 1)
  - City Hall, Built of White Marble, at Brooklyn, Long Island, N.Y. Gleason's Pictorial Drawing Room Companion, undated. (Box 1)
  - Clarence Walker Seamans Residence, 789 St. Mark's Avenue. King's Views of Brooklyn, 1904 (Box 1)
  - A Colonial Residence in the Borough of Brooklyn, New York City. Mr. George Palliser, Architect [multiple images]. Scientific American, 1901-05 (Box 1)
  - A Colonial Residence at Flatbush, L.I. Scientific American, 1901-04 (Box 1)
  - The Cornell-Pierrepont Mansion [rear view]. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884 (Box 1)
  - A Cottage Near Brooklyn, N.Y. Scientific American, 1189-01 (Box 1)
  - The De Hart, or Bergen House. Stiles, History of Kings County (Box 1)
  - Design for the New Post Office and U.S. Courts, New York City. Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, 1868-03-21 (Box 1)
  - Desmond Dunne Residence, 25 Prospect Park West. King's Views of Brooklyn, 1904 (Box 1)
  - A Dwelling at Bensonhurst, Long Island. Mr. John J. Petit, Architect. Scientific American, 1901-12 (Box 1)
  - A Dwelling at Dyker Heights, Borough of Brooklyn, N.Y. Mr. C. Schubert, Architect. Scientific American, 1901-07 (Box 1)
  - A Dwelling at Dyker Heights, Borough of Brooklyn, N.Y. Mr. C. Schubert, Architect. Scientific American, 1901-08 (Box 1)
  - A Dwelling at Flatbush, N.Y. [including plans]. Scientific American, 1886-08 (Box 1)
  - E. Greenfield's Son & Co. Manufacturers of Confectionery and Chocolates, 101 to 111 Lorimer St. King's Views of Brooklyn, 1904 (Box 1)
  - E.W. Bliss Company. King's Views of Brooklyn, 1904 (Box 1)
  - Eberhard Faber Pencil Company, Greenpoint Ave., Kent, and West Sts. King's Views of Brooklyn, 1904 (Box 1)
  - Edward H. Lichfield Residence, 2 Montague Terrace. King's Views of Brooklyn, 1904 (Box 1)
  - Edwin E. Jackson, Jr., Residence, 424 Clinton Avenue. King's Views of Brooklyn, 1904 (Box 1)
  - An Elizabethan Music Room in Residence of L.H. Moore, Esq., Borough of Brooklyn, N.Y. Mr. John J. Petit, Architect. Scientific American, 1901-07 (Box 1)
  - F. Wesel Manufacturing Co., 70-80 Cranberry Street. King's Views of Brooklyn, 1904 (Box 1)
  - Florence Court, Pierrepont and Hicks Streets. King's Views of Brooklyn, 1904 (Box 1)
  - Former Residence of the Late Edward Ridley, Undated. (Box 1)
  - Frank S. Jones Residence, 790 St. Mark's Avenue. King's Views of Brooklyn, 1904 (Box 1)
  - Fred C. Cocheu Residence, Fort Hamilton Avenue and 75th Street. King's Views of Brooklyn, 1904 (Box 1)
  - Frederick A.M. Burrell Residence, 1409 Albermale Road. King's Views of Brooklyn, 1904 (Box 1)
  - Frederick B. Pratt Residence, 229 Clinton Avenue. King's Views of Brooklyn, 1904 (Box 1)
  - Frederick Loeser & Company Department Store. King's Views of Brooklyn, 1904 (Box 1)
  - A Gambrel-Roofed Residence at Dyker Heights, Brooklyn N.Y. Mr. C. Schubert, Architect. Scientific American, 1901-02 (Box 1)
  - Garfield Place, Brooklyn, N.Y. American Architect and Building News, 1892-01-30 (Box 1)
  - George D. Pratt Residence, 245 Clinton Avenue. King's Views of Brooklyn, 1904 (Box 1)
  - George P. Tangeman Residence, 276 Berkeley Place. King's Views of Brooklyn, 1904 (Box 1)
  - Grand Union Tea Company, Pearl, Water, and Front Streets. King's Views of Brooklyn, 1904 (Box 1)
  - H. Batterman Department Store, and Broadway Bank. King's Views of Brooklyn, 1904 (Box 1)
  - H.G. Friedmann, New York Model Bakery, Bedford Avenue and North 11th Street. King's Views of Brooklyn, 1904 (Box 1)
  - Hebrew Orphan Asylum. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884 (Box 1)
  - Hecla Iron Works. King's Views of Brooklyn (Box 1)
  - Henry Carlton Hulbert Residence, Prospect Park West. King's Views of Brooklyn, 1904 (Box 1)
  - Hotel St. George. King's Views of Brooklyn, 1904 (Box 1)
  - A House at Bensonhurst, L.I.; Mr. C. Schubert, Architect. Scientific American, 1904-05 (Box 1)
  - A House at Prospect Park South, Brooklyn, N.Y.; Mr. John J. Petit, Architect. Scientific American, 1903-01 (Box 1)
  - House of Guido Plessner, ESQ., Lincoln Place and Plaza Street, Brooklyn, N.Y. American Architect and Building News, 1892-03-12 (Box 1)
  - Houses on Jefferson Avenue Between Patchen and Ralph Aves Brooklyn. For Chas. E. Palmer, Esq. American Architect and Building News, 1893-03-25 (Box 1)
  - Imperial Apartment House, Bedford Avenue and Dean Street. King's Views of Brooklyn, 1904 (Box 1)
  - Industrial School and Home of Brooklyn, E.D. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884 (Box 1)
  - James McMahon Residence. King's Views of Brooklyn, 1904 (Box 1)
  - James W. Edgett's Restaurant, Fulton Street and Flatbush Avenue. King's Views of Brooklyn, 1904 (Box 1)
  - Jennings Lace Works, Park Avenue and Hall Street. King's Views of Brooklyn, 1904 (Box 1)
  - John Gibb Residence, 218 Gates Avenue. King's Views of Brooklyn, 1904 (Box 1)
  - John Rogers Maxwell Residence, 78 Eighth Avenue, near Union Street. King's Views of Brooklyn, 1904 (Box 1)
  - The Johnson House. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884 (Box 1)
  - A Japanese House and Garden; Messrs. Petit & Green, Architects., Undated. (Box 1)
  - Junction of Fulton Street and DeKalb Avenue. King's Views of Brooklyn, 1904 (Box 1)
  - Kings County Courthouse Brooklyn Harper's Weekly, 1865-03-04 (Box 1)
  - Knox Hat Factory, St.Mark's and Grand Avenue. King's Views of Brooklyn, 1904 (Box 1)
  - Long Island College Hospital. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884 (Box 1)
  - The Long Island Historical Society. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884 (Box 1)
  - The Maresi Co., Confectioners, 30 Clinton Street. King's Views of Brooklyn, 1904 (Box 1)
  - Marshall Sylvanus Driggs Residence, 279 Washington Avenue. King's Views of Brooklyn, 1904 (Box 1)
  - The McLoughlin Brothers, South 11th and Berry Streets. King's Views of Brooklyn, 1904 (Box 1)
  - Melrose Hall, 1883. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884 (Box 1)
  - The Mercantile Library, Brooklyn, L.I.; Mr. P.B. Wight, Architect. The New York Sketchbook of Architecture, 1876 (Box 1)
  - The Methodist General Hospital, Brooklyn, New York—From a Photograph by Pach Brothers. Harper's Weekly, 1888-01-07 (Box 1)
  - The Mills-Platt Co. Building, Pierrepont Art Rooms, 44 Clinton Street. King's Views of Brooklyn, 1904 (Box 1)
  - A Modern Dwelling at Dyker Heights, Brooklyn, N.Y.; Mr. C. Schubert, Architect. Scientific American, 1901-04 (Box 1)
  - A Modern Residence at Flatbush, L.I.; Mr. Benjamin Driesler, Architect. Scientific American, 1901-02 (Box 1)
  - The Mohawk, Washington Avenue. King's Views of Brooklyn, 1904 (Box 1)
  - The Montague. Apartment Hotel, 103-105 Montague Street. King's Views of Brooklyn, 1904 (Box 1)
  - Montague Street, North Side, Clinton to Court Streets. King's Views of Brooklyn, 1904 (Box 1)
  - Mrs. Charles Pratt Residence. King's Views of Brooklyn, 1904 (Box 1)
  - New Apartment House, Brooklyn, N.Y. Scientific American, 1888-12-22 (Box 1)
  - New Brooklyn Armories—Drawn by H.D. Nichols. Harper's Weekly, 1892-07-16 (Box 1)
  - New Building of the Municipal Department of Brooklyn. Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, 1879-04-05 (Box 1)
  - New Clubs and Dwelling Houses of Brooklyn. Harper's Weekly, 1889-08-24 (Box 1)
  - The New Eagle Building [oversize – not in folder, framed in Reserve Room]. Brooklyn Daily Eagle, 1892-07-27 (Box 1)
  - The New Mercantile Library Building, Brooklyn, N.Y. Harper's Weekly, 1869-02-16 (Box 1)
  - The New Post Office, Brooklyn, N.Y. Scientific American, 1886-03 (Box 1)
  - The Newsboys' Home of the Brooklyn Children's Aid Society. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884 (Box 1)
  - Niels Poulson Residence, Bay Ridge. Interior View. King's Views of Brooklyn, 1904 (Box 1)
  - Niels Poulson Residence, Shore Road and 89th Street, Bay Ridge. King's Views of Brooklyn, 1904 (Box 1)
  - Ocean View of the "Inebriates Home," Fort Hamilton. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884 (Box 1)
  - Old Homestead of the Wyckoff Family, Flushing Avenue, E.D. Brooklyn, N.Y., Undated. (Box 1)
  - Old House in Brooklyn, Once Occupied by Major Andre – From a Sketch by Charles Mente. Harper's Weekly, 1877-05-26 (Box 1)
  - Orphans' Home, on the Church Charity Foundation. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884 (Box 1)
  - "Owl's Head." Residence of E.W. Bliss, Esq., at Bay Ridge L.I. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884 (Box 1)
  - Packer Collegiate Institute, Joralemon Street, Brooklyn Heights, N.Y. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884 (Box 1)
  - The Pool of Brooklyn's St.George Hotel, 1930 (Box 1)
  - Proposed Memorial Campanile for Plaza of Prospect Park, Brooklyn N.Y.; Henry O. Avery, Architect. Scientific American, 1889-02 (Box 1)
  - A Queen Anne Cottage at Flatbush, Long Island. Scientific American, 1889-01 (Box 1)
  - A Queen Anne Cottage at Flatbush, Long Island. Scientific American, 1889-02 (Box 1)
  - A Residence at Dyker Heights, Brooklyn N.Y.; Mr. John J. Petit, Architect. Scientific American, 1901-06 (Box 1)
  - A Residence at Flatbush, Brooklyn, N.Y.; Mr. John J. Petit, Architect. Scientific American, 1903-09 (Box 1)
  - A Residence in Flatbush, Brooklyn, N.Y.; Messrs. Barber & Klutz, Architects. Scientific American, 1904-02 (Box 1)
  - Residence of Mrs. M.E. Smith, Prospect Park South, Brooklyn, N.Y.; Mr. John J. Petit, Architect. Scientific American, 1903-10 (Box 1)
  - A Residence at Prospect Park South, Brooklyn, N.Y.; Mr. John J. Petit, Architect. Scientific American, 1903-04 (Box 1)
  - A Residence at Prospect Park South, Brooklyn, N.Y.; Mr. J.J. Petit, Architect. Scientific American, 1903-07 (Box 1)
  - A Residence at Sea Gate, L.I.; Messrs. Parfitt Brothers, Architects. Scientific American, 1901-07 (Box 1)
  - A Residence at West Brooklyn. Scientific American, 1890-07-01 (Box 1)
  - Residence of the Late Edward Ridley., Undated. (Box 1)
  - The Residence of Rev. A.P. Stockwell. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884 (Box 1)
  - Richard Young Residence, 87 Lincoln Road, near Prospect Park. King's Views of Brooklyn, 1904 (Box 1)
  - Sackett & Wilhelms Lithographing and Printing Co., Grand Street and Morgan Ave. King's Views of Brooklyn, 1904 (Box 1)
  - Saint Gregory's Church, Brooklyn, N.Y.; Helmle & Corbett, Architects [multiple images, interiors & exteriors]. The American Architect, 1917-12-05 (Box 1)
  - St. John's Hospital, on the Church Charity Foundation. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884 (Box 1)
  - The St. John's Male Orphan Asylum. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884 (Box 1)
  - St. John's R.C. College, Willoughby Avenue, Corner of Lewis Avenue. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884 (Box 1)
  - The Schermerhorn House. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884 (Box 1)
  - "Sea Breeze" – New Utrecht, Kings County, L.I. – Summer Residence of Dr. S. Fleet Speir. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884 (Box 1)
  - The Shelter in Prospect Park. King's Views of Brooklyn, 1904 (Box 1)
  - A Spanish House at Prospect Park South, Brooklyn, N.Y. Scientific American, 1903-06 (Box 1)
  - Standish Arms. Apartment Hotel, 167-171 Columbia Heights. King's Views of Brooklyn, 1904 (Box 1)
  - The Stillwell House. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884 (Box 1)
  - Street Front of the Brooklyn Library. Scientific American, 1889-08 (Box 1)
  - The Stryker House. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884 (Box 1)
  - A Summer Residence at Sea Gate, Borough of Brooklyn, N.Y.; Messrs. Rossiter & Wright, Architects. Scientific American, 1901-09 (Box 1)
  - A Summer House at Sea Gate, N.Y.; Mr. Frank T. Cornell, Architect. Scientific American, 1901-06 (Box 1)
  - A Summer House at Sea Gate, Norton's Point, L.I.; Mr. Charles W. Romeyn, Architect. Scientific American, 1901-10 (Box 1)
  - A Summer Residence at Sea Gate, L.I. Messrs. Parfitt Brothers, Architects. Scientific American, 1901-05 (Box 1)
  - Superintendents of the Poor Lunatic Asylum. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884 (Box 1)
  - Superintendents of the Poor Hospital. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884 (Box 1)
  - Superintendents of the Poor Alms-House. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884 (Box 1)
  - A Swiss Chalet at Prospect Park South, Brooklyn, N.Y.; Mr. John J. Petit, Architect. Scientific American, 1903-03 (Box 1)
  - Temporary Home For Friendless Women and Children. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884 (Box 1)
  - Three New Buildings for Brooklyn: Boys' High School, 23rd Regiment NGSNY Armory,13th Regiment Armory. Harper's Weekly, 1890-08-09 (Box 1)
  - The Touraine, 21 Clinton Street, between Franklin and Pierrepont Streets. King's Views of Brooklyn, 1904 (Box 1)
  - Two Bay Windows: Residence of Dean Alvord, Esq., Prospect Park South, Brooklyn, N.Y. Scientific American, 1903-05 (Box 1)
  - The Vechte-Cortelyou House. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884 (Box 1)
  - Views at West Brooklyn. Supplement to Building and Loan News, 1890-04 (Box 1)
  - A Villa Near New York [house in Flatbush]. Scientific American (Box 1)
  - Washington's Quarters at Gowanus, Brooklyn, 1840 (Box 1)
  - William A. Engeman Residence, 105 Buckingham Road, near Prospect Park. King's Views of Brooklyn, 1904 (Box 1)
  - William B.A. Jurgens, Wholesale Grocer, Flushing Avenue and Ryerson Street. King's Views of Brooklyn, 1904 (Box 1)
  - William Berri Residence, 467 Clinton Avenue. King's Views of Brooklyn, 1904 (Box 1)
  - Williamsburgh Savings Bank. Stiles, History of Kings County, 1884 (Box 1)
  - The Williamsburgh Savings Bank; Mr. George B. Post, Architect. The New York Sketchbook of Architecture, 1874 (Box 1)
- Battleships
  - Battle-Ship "Indiana," with Crew of 450, in Brooklyn Dry Dock. Leslie's Weekly, 1903 June 25 (Box 1)
  - Ericsson's Torpedo Boat "Destroyer," Now Undergoing Firing Tests at the Brooklyn Navy Yard. Once A Week, 1892-07-09 (Box 1)
  - Fitting up the Second-Class Battleship "Texas" at the Brooklyn Navy Yard. Collier's Weekly, 1895 (Box 1)
  - Launching the $4,200,000 Battle-ship "Connecticut." Leslie's Weekly, 1904-10-13 (Box 1)
  - Launch of the Armored Cruiser "Maine" at the Brooklyn Navy-Yard, drawn by J.O. Davidson. Harper's Weekly, 1890-11-29 (Box 1)
  - Launch of the US Steam Frigate "Niagara" Navy Yard, Brooklyn NY. Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, 1856-03-08 (Box 1)
  - Sinking of the "Texas" at Cob Dock, Brooklyn. Collier's Weekly, 1896-11-19 (Box 1)
  - U.S. Battleship "Indiana," N.Y. Harbor., Undated. (Box 1)
  - The United States Sloop of War "Brooklyn." Harper's Weekly, 1861-01-19 (Box 1)
- Beecher, Henry Ward
  - 2nd Edition Pictorial History of the Beecher-Tilton Scandal. Its Origin, Progress and Trial, Illustrated with Fifty Engravings from Accurate Sketches, undated (Box 2)
  - The Attack on Frank Moulton. Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, September 12, 1874 (Box 2)
  - The Beecher-Tilton Case [various scenes]. Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, August 8, 1874 (Box 2)
  - The Beecher-Tilton Case – The Rev. Henry Ward Beecher at the Door of Plymouth Church Lecture-Room, During the Exercises of the Friday Evening Prayer Meeting, on August 14th. Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, September 5, 1874 (Box 2)
  - The Beecher-Tilton Case – Theodore Tilton Reading His Statement to the Committee of Investigation of Plymouth Church. Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, August 8, 1874 (Box 2)
  - The Beecher-Tilton Investigation [The Residence of Mr. Storrs in Monroe Place, Where Mr. Tilton Read His Statement on Monday Night]. The Daily Graphic, July 22, 1874 (Box 2)
  - The Beecher-Tilton Scandal [various scenes; color illustrations; German language]. Frank Leslie's Illustrierte Zeitung (Box 2)
  - The Beecher-Tilton Scandal [various scenes] (Box 2)
  - Beecher's Churches. Harper's Weekly, August 11, 1866 (Box 2)
  - Beecher's Theorie und Praxis [in German and English. Mayer, Merkel & Ottman Lith. 22&24 Church St. N.Y.] (Box 2)
  - The Beecher Statue in Front of the City Hall, Brooklyn. Harper's Weekly, June 27, 1891 (Box 2)
  - The Brooklyn Battle – Blows to be Given as Well as Taken. The Daily Graphic, August 15, 1874 (Box 2)
  - Casting the Statue of Henry Ward Beecher. [ Scientific American], June 27, 1891 (Box 2)
  - The Church in Lawrenceburg in Which Mr. Beecher First Preached. Published by Johnson, Fry & Co. Publishers, New York (Box 2)
  - The Congregational Council in Doctor Buddington's church, Clinton Avenue, Brooklyn – Trial of Plymouth Church for its Secession – Rev. Doctors Storrs speaking in relation to the Rev. Henry Ward Beecher (Box 2)
  - Cutting Up The Brooklyn Cheese. Judge, February 26, 1887 (Box 2)
  - The Death and Obsequies of Henry Ward Beecher – The Funeral Procession on its Way to Plymouth Church; The 13th Regiment Saluting the Remains of its Deceased Chaplain at his Late Residence. Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, March 19, 1887 (Box 2)
  - Discord Amongst the Angels. Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, October 24, 1874 (Box 2)
  - Effects of the Brooklyn Church Revival: Reference to the Scandal Causes the Gushing Pastor, Beecher, to Weep – His Lady Members Come to the Rescue and Soothe the Old Dominie in his Tearful Trouble. The National Police Gazette: New York, March 26, 1881 (Box 2)
  - Freedom's Champion at Home, and the Country's Defender Abroad. Judge, March 19,1887 (Box 2)
  - The Funeral Rites of Henry Ward Beecher – Bearing the Body into Plymouth Church; The People Awaiting Their Turn to Enter the Church; The Receiving Vault in Greenwood. Harper's Weekly, March 19, 1887 (Box 2)
  - The Funeral Rites of Henry Ward Beecher – Lying in State in Plymouth Church. Harper's Weekly, March 19, 1887 (Box 2)
  - Giving Out Henry Ward Beecher's Statement to the Press, at Mr. Raymond's House in Henry Street, Brooklyn, on Thursday Evening, 1874 [?] (Box 2)
  - Gulliver and the Party Liliputians. – They Cannot Bind Him. Puck, 1885 (Box 2)
  - Henry Ward Beecher [from a Picture by F. Dielman]. Harper's Weekly, March 12, 1887 (Box 2)
  - Henry Ward Beecher. Engraving by H.C. McRae after painting by T. Hicks (Box 2)
  - Henry Ward Beecher, from the original painting by Chappel. Published by Johnson, Fry & Co. Publishers, New York, 1862 (Box 2)
  - Henry Ward Beecher and Harriet Beecher Stowe. Harper's Weekly, October 30, 1869 (Box 2)
  - Henry Ward Beecher's Bread and Water Extra (Box 2)
  - "He Takes It Pretty Easy." – The Rev. Henry Ward Beecher, on The Evening of August 12th, Sitting and Joking on the Door-Steps of His Residence. Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, August 29, 1874 (Box 2)
  - The Interview between Henry Ward Beecher and Frank D. Moulton, in the Parlor of the Latter; and The Meeting of Messrs. Moulton, Beecher and Tilton in Mr. Moulton's Bedroom. Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, February 20, 1875 (Box 2)
  - Lyman Beecher, D.D. Drawn by S. Wallin, from a daguerreotype by M.M. Lawrence. Engraved on Wood by N. Orr (Box 2)
  - "A Man's Amusements Should Be The Opposite of His Daily Occupation." – Henry Ward Beecher's Recent Lecture Illustrated. Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, February 22, 1879 (Box 2)
  - New York - Reception of Henry Ward Beecher at the Brooklyn Academy of Music, June 25th, on the occasion of his 70th birthday, Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, July 7, 1883 (Box 2)